<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blood Pressure Log</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_explained">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string-array name="arm_array">
        <item>Left Arm</item>
        <item>Right Arm</item>
        <item>Left Wrist</item>
        <item>Right Wrist</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="posture_array">
        <item>Sitting down</item>
        <item>Lying Down</item>
        <item>Semi-reclined</item>
        <item>Standing up</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>

    <string name="number_mean">
        What do the numbers mean?
        \n\nEveryone would like to have healthy blood pressure. But what exactly does that mean?

        When your doctor takes your blood pressure, it’s expressed as a measurement with two numbers, with one number on top (systolic) and one on the bottom (diastolic), like a fraction. For example, 120/80 mm Hg.

        The top number refers to the amount of pressure in your arteries during the contraction of your heart muscle. This is called systolic pressure.

        The bottom number refers to your blood pressure when your heart muscle is between beats. This is called diastolic pressure.

        Both numbers are important in determining the state of your heart health.

        Numbers greater than the ideal range indicate that your heart is working too hard to pump blood to the rest of your body.
    </string>
    <string name="normal">
        What’s a normal reading?
        \n\nFor a normal reading, your blood pressure needs to show a top number (systolic pressure) that’s between 90 and less than 120 and a bottom number (diastolic pressure) that’s between 60 and less than 80. The American Heart Association (AHA) considers blood pressure to be within the normal range when both your systolic and diastolic numbers are in these ranges.

Blood pressure readings are expressed in millimeters of mercury. This unit is abbreviated as mm Hg. A normal reading would be any blood pressure below 120/80 mm Hg and above 90/60 mm Hg in an adult.

If you’re in the normal range, no medical intervention is needed. However, you should maintain a healthy lifestyle and healthy weight to help prevent hypertension from developing. Regular exercise and healthy eating can also help. You may need to be even more mindful of your lifestyle if hypertension runs in your family.
    </string>

    <string name="elevated">
        Elevated blood pressure
        \n\nNumbers higher than 120/80 mm Hg are a red flag that you need to take on heart-healthy habits.

When your systolic pressure is between 120 and 129 mm Hg and your diastolic pressure is less than 80 mm Hg, it means you have elevated blood pressure.

Although these numbers aren’t technically considered high blood pressure, you’ve moved out of the normal range. Elevated blood pressure has a good chance of turning into actual high blood pressure, which puts you at an increased risk of heart disease and stroke.

No medications are necessary for elevated blood pressure. But this is when you should adopt healthier lifestyle choices. A balanced diet and regular exercise can help lower your blood pressure to a healthy range and help prevent elevated blood pressure from developing into full-fledged hypertension.
    </string>

    <string name="high1">
        High Blood Pressure Stage-1
        \n\nYou’ll generally be diagnosed with high blood pressure if your systolic blood pressure reaches between 130 and 139 mm Hg, or if your diastolic blood pressure reaches between 80 and 89 mm Hg. This is considered stage 1 hypertension.

However, the AHA notes that if you get only one reading this high, you may not truly have high blood pressure. What determines the diagnosis of hypertension at any stage is the average of your numbers over a period of time.

Your doctor can help you measure and track your blood pressure to confirm whether it’s too high. You may need to start taking medications if your blood pressure doesn’t improve after one month of following a healthy lifestyle, especially if you’re already at high risk for heart disease. If you’re at lower risk, your doctor may want to follow up in three to six months after you’ve adopted more healthy habits.

If you’re 65 years or older and otherwise healthy, your doctor will likely recommend treatment and lifestyle changes once your systolic blood pressure is greater than 130 mm Hg. The treatment for adults 65 and older who have significant health problems should be made on a case-by-case basis.
    </string>

    <string name="high2">
        High Blood Pressure Stage-2
        \n\nStage 2 high blood pressure indicates an even more serious condition. If your blood pressure reading shows a top number of 140 or more, or a bottom number of 90 or more, it’s considered stage 2 hypertension.

At this stage, your doctor will recommend one or more medications for keeping your blood pressure under control. But you shouldn’t rely solely on medications to treat hypertension. Lifestyle habits are just as important in stage 2 as they are in the other stages.

    </string>

    <string name="emergency">
        Emergency
        \n\nA blood pressure reading above 180/120 mm Hg indicates a serious health problem. The AHA refers to these high measurements as a “hypertensive crisis.” Blood pressure in this range requires urgent treatment even if there are no accompanying symptoms.

You should seek emergency treatment if you have blood pressure in this range, which may accompany symptoms such as:

chest pain
shortness of breath
visual changes
symptoms of stroke, such as paralysis or a loss of muscle control in the face or an extremity
blood in your urine
dizziness
headache
    </string>
</resources>